hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and this podcast is talk
about ways for you to grow in your life
and in your business today I want to
help you break past what's been stopping
you if you're running into setbacks so
that you can start to experience
breakthrough in your life one of the
things that I want to share with you is
the fact that I think we all run into
setbacks and it's not rare at all as a
business owner to have setbacks doesn't
mean that you're failing doesn't mean
that you're a failure I myself have had
numerous setbacks in my life and my
business but it's what we do with those
situations that Define us and so today I
want to talk about just what are some of
those things that you can do to get you
back going again we know what it's like
you're making momentum you're growing
you're reaching that goal you hit a
level that's greater than you've ever
hit before and then boom something
knocks you back down to the previous
level that you were at can be
devastating you feel like you've lost
time you feel like you'll never get back
there again I can tell you as somebody
who's had that happen to them numerous
times and and and you know it's
interesting years ago I used to pride
myself in not having this and and gosh I
was just living a play it safe life is
what it was when you're actually going
out there doing something when you're
actually making a difference running
into setbacks is a normal part of the
process so hold yourself accountable
number one that's great great but number
two give yourself
Grace give yourself Grace that it's okay
and love yourself through it have
self-compassion through those situations
one of the beautiful things that happens
when we have a setback is this is that
how how much more bad can it get now yes
we know it can get bad right we can come
up with it in our head but here's what I
see is you might as well just take a
risk at that
point and you will come to the moment
where you're like you know what I might
as well just put myself out there
nothing else has worked up to this
moment in time and the pain of inaction
is worse than the pain of what might
happen if I don't do this perfectly
giving up perfectionism realizing that
perfectionism is just a facade is one of
the number one things that can break us
through when we have setbacks and they
happen they really do but realizing that
they are what is preparing you and
growing you and keeping you moving
forward to your goals
that is one of the most beautiful things
you I look back at my life and I look
back at moments where I felt like I was
knocked off the horse and things were
not going my way and I and and and I
thought I was making forward momentum
and I got knocked back in fact this even
happened in my own life over the last
eight months it has my business is great
we're doing great business is wonderful
but I found out that my my wife was
pregnant and this was a
huge exciting news for us we were very
excited to hear this but at the same
time it was like
whoa
huh I got to get some things in order in
my
life this Baby's on the way and what
ended up happening was I ended up
self-sabotaging in some different ways
and things that I thought I was making
momentum on I ended up striking out on
and the same thing happened when my son
was born and and it felt like I was I
had I had literally built my business to
making over seven figures and then I
started to shrink back out of fear and
worry of losing it
all and this created a self-fulfilling
prophecy in my life I started paying
attention to all the negative I started
looking at how everything wasn't working
out and I started feeling like gosh
nothing never works out for
me how many of you have experienced this
in your life were you were you
you thought you were making great
momentum and maybe you're listening to
me right now listen if you lose trust in
me or you think negatively of me because
I'm sharing
this I I'm not going to please you
there's nothing I can say that's going
to please you
okay because you're not living in
reality but if you're somebody who
actually lives on planet Earth and you
know that listen not everything is all
sunshine and rainbows but it's not about
how you hard you get hit but what
happens when you can get up when the
Hits
come that's what defines you and that's
what changes you and that's what creates
the kind of life that you want and so
what's really awesome to do is it's it's
exciting to be able to make some big
changes when those things
happen get your health in order start
sleeping more start journaling pay
attention to what friends you're
spending time with pay attention to what
media you're consuming now by the way
I'm not anti-media I I actually enjoy
watching movies and even playing video
games and reading novels it actually
helps my brain decompress when I'm when
I'm at at I'm going so high and so fast
and at such a high energy in my business
that actually being able to do some of
those things actually helps kind of
bring some some clarity in my life and I
actually Thrive when I give myself
moments like that I actually Thrive when
I give myself moments of of play fun and
enjoyment but setbacks are not the end
of the world they're actually a setup
for things to get better for
you and when you start to understand
that your life gets a whole lot better
we stop living in the woe is me
mindset and we start saying what's
possible for me and we start looking at
the
possibilities as they start to come
in you know I want you to look back
at the greatest moment in your life
where you had the most success
ever and you were just on top of the
world and everything was going amazing
that that moment could be right now
while you're listening to
this what happened after
that and then what did you do to get
back on the horse moving forward you
might say well I'm I'm I'm at the lowest
point of my life right now Jeremiah I
don't know if I can get back on the
horse and move forward you know this
this happened to me in a moment in time
where I I was on paper I was about to
become a multi-millionaire through a
business deal that I had done and then
that business deal was removed from me
and I felt like I had lost everything
and lost all of my confidence and all
the ability to even do anything in my
business as far as that goes I thought
that I had no value to deliver to
people this was
about six and a half years
ago gosh that was a while ago
and I and it took me took me four years
to to even like recover in that moment
it one of the hardest things I ever
did but through that I realized that it
was preparing me for something better
than what I was experiencing then back
then I was drinking back then I was
hanging out with people that I'm not
proud about back then my goals my dreams
my vision I had just gotten married they
were different than they are today and I
can tell you that every single setback
that I've ever had in my life has set me
up for a better tomorrow as far as it
goes so now I start to get excited
anytime a setback happens I'm not trying
to create setbacks gosh that's silly
right don't try to do that don't try to
create them I'll tell you I
actually did that a little
bit wouldn't encourage it
okay because I was getting so excited
about the fact that the setbacks were
happening I was like oh crap this isn't
the smart thing to do
okay then you get back on the horse
again you start saying you know
what things are going to get better and
then they start to because you start
declaring you start having a vision for
where you're going you start to see
things getting better for you and so one
of the number one things that we can do
is that we start to see in our Mind's
Eye things working out in our favor in
our
life things will start to work out in
your favor if you
believe that they will so it starts with
the belief internally with you and then
you got to take action when it feels
uncomfortable and this is the hard work
part about about it is you got to figure
out how to pull out of yourself from the
middle of the muck that genius that's
held beneath the surface you know we all
all have a level of Genius but often
times we hold it behind Pain and
experiences and we don't want to get
burned again and we don't want bad
things to happen and we don't want to
get our hopes up but can I tell you this
that by getting your hopes up great
things can happen in your life and you
can start to come together and start to
experience those
things again life isn't all sunshine and
rainbows but anytime that there's a
setback it becomes a
setup for you to do something greater
next time for you to look at okay what
not to do right let's think practically
about it let's get out of our emotional
mind and actually think logically about
it think about truth have somebody in
your life that you can work with have
somebody in your life that can call you
up to a higher level have a close friend
that can speak life into you start to
believe that things can become better
for you now again it might not seem like
tomorrow could ever be
better and you might feel like
tomorrow's never going to get
better and it's always just going to be
crappy and it's always just going to be
a struggle and it's always just going to
be in the muck because in the moment we
feel that way but can I tell you as soon
as you shift your perspective towards
what is the lesson in this this isn't a
failure this is a learning experience
and what can I learn from this and we
start to move into learning learning
experience mode and we start asking
mentors and trainers and coaches and
people to help us through these things
we start to Humble ourselves and say Hey
listen I need some help so I don't
repeat this again and then you start to
become willing to take a risk again you
start to become willing to step out in
faith you start to become willing to try
the thing that maybe terrified you the
most in the
past
again and that breakthrough starts to
happen in your life beautiful things
start to come out of it the things that
you only ever dreamed of start to happen
because you start seeing them and then
experiencing them them because your
actions start following the vision that
you have without a vision you won't have
action so you have to tether a vision of
a better tomorrow in your mind and then
start acting as if that is happening
today it's not about fake it till you
make it at all it's about believing that
you are on the right path path to the
great things to
happen and again you might say this
sounds like a bunch of personal
development motivational mumbo jumbo
it's not because I used to think that I
used to think that for the longest
time but I can tell you as somebody
who's walked through
hellenbach multiple times because of my
own
stupidity that every time that I was
humbled myself and said you know what
what's the lesson in this and I said let
me take action and stop letting my fear
and my worry run my life and start to do
something that I feared and start to do
something that's going to take me to
that next breakthrough I started to
experience better things in my life and
I believe that the same can happen for
you as well that no matter what setbacks
you
have there's always a better and
brighter tomorrow all right listen this
has been the grow Your Life podcast stay
plugged in if if you're a coach if
you're a mentor if you're a trainer I'd
love to work with you in my accelerator
program that's why I help coaches
mentors and trainers scale their
businesses to tens of millions of
dollars online and I can help you make
your first 10 to $225,000 online even if
you're just starting out we got systems
we got trainings I'll coach you I'll be
in there personally as part of your team
to walk you through that process and
joining with you to become part of your
future success strategy I'll see you in
there everybody grow your life we'll
talk soon right
[Music]
[Applause]